<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>isaac-champions</name>
    <directory>isaac-champions</directory>
    <id>3057506609</id>
    <description>It's not another C side... it's an A+ side! Introducing...

[h1] Isaac Champions! [/h1] 
This mod adds champion variants of (almost) every character, tainted or not! Champion characters start with a different item and stat loadout than their vanilla counterpart, but still count for the same completion marks as them. Champion chars were meant to be played after completing the game and starting a new save file, giving you a fresh way to relive the classics while grinding for the next dead god, but don't let that stop you, play how you want!

[h1] Champion Crown [/h1] 
Starting a run as a champion character is super simple, all you need to do is pickup the [b]Champion Crown[/b] item at the beginning of the run and you'll be all champed up! Be careful though, as leaving the room and coming back will make the pedestal go away.

[h1] Champion Characters [/h1] 
Currently, [b]21[/b] champion characters are completed. A full list of their effects can be found [url=https://github.com/Kattacka/isaac-champions/blob/main/README.md]HERE[/url]. Champion characters come with changed stats, items, trinkets, and sometimes even mechanics. All changes use vanilla items and mechanics only, so now you can explore the amazing hidden synergy potential of items you never get to use! I don't have any ideas for any more characters at this point, so feel free to suggest more with these limitations in mind.

Fully compatible with External Item Descriptions! Check the crown to see the effects of each character!

As always, use the discussion threads below for any bug reports or suggestions. I hope you enjoy champions!

Special thanks to Eucalyptus for playtesting and code support, and to Ferpe for the thumbnail and crown sprite.

[h1] Incompatibilities [/h1] 
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2865017190]Better Moving Box[/url] (Makes Isaac+'s moving box be unpocketed) 
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3007547144]Smelter Unlocks Marbles Too[/url] (Breaks starting trinkets smelting)
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3035686305]Devoid: Apollyon Rework[/url] (The reworked void can't absorb items)
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2560433301]Treasure Room Start[/url] (Crashes the game, but just use [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2552169074]Adjacent Starting Treasure[/url] instead)
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2665189152]Mantle Rework[/url] (Makes it impossible to remove holy mantle from the lost)

</description>
    <version>1.11</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
